So this fissure was left by your training.
（衝撃音）
Like a fairy tale
It's a sign the story has reached its end
（フェルン）
これは 修行の跡だったのですね
Like a single passage taken from
A journey that was too long
Of the evil that once cast a shadow
♪～
Across this land
And the memories of the short journey
～♪
With the hero who defeated it
Beyond Journey's End
The story ends
And the hero goes to sleep
（フェルン）
竜と戦う気はないのですよね？
Leaving this land with
なぜ 修行を続けているのですか？
Days of peace and quiet
The passage of time heartlessly
（シュタルク）
俺が この村に来た時
Makes people forget
みんな 辛気くさい顔をして
Even the tracks left behind by his life
竜の恐怖に おびえていた
Begin to rust
そんな連中がさ
Just the same
今では 幸せそうに笑ってるんだよ
Your words and wishes and courage
“シュタルク様がいるから
この村は大丈夫だ”ってな
Are still inside of me
And they live on
俺は何もしてないってのによ
We chose the same path
この村が襲われていないのは
That's all it was supposed to be
ただの竜の気まぐれだ
Why is it that at some point
I wanted to understand the reason for
The tears that fall down my cheeks
（フェルン）竜が村を襲ったら
Even now
If I retrace the journey we walked together
シュタルク様は戦うのですか？
Even though you're not there
（シュタルク）死んだって嫌さ
でもよ
I know I'll be able to find it
Episode 6: The Hero of the Village
You don't intend to fight
the dragon, do you?
So why do you continue training?
When I arrived here,
all the villagers wore grim expressions
and lived in fear of the dragon.
Now those same people are smiling happily.
They say this village is safe
because I'm around,
even though I haven't done anything.
The dragon simply hasn't attacked this
village because it doesn't feel like it.
If the dragon attacks the village,
will you fight it?
I don't want to die.
But to the people of this village,
I'm a hero.
この村の連中にとっては
俺は英雄なんだよ
この村の英雄 シュタルクなんだ
I'm Stark, the hero of this village.
俺が守らなきゃならないんだよ
I have to defend it.
とは言ってみたが…
That said, maybe I'd actually run away.
実際は逃げだしちまうかもな
額の傷だって
I got this scar on my forehead during a
fight with my master, not against monsters.
魔物と戦いたくなくて
師匠とケンカした時に
できたものだ
殴られたのは
あの時が初めてだったな
That was the first time he ever hit me.
俺に失望したんだろうさ
He must've been disappointed in me.
結局…
In the end, he never praised me. Not once.
俺は師匠に 一度だって
褒められたことはなかった
何だよ
What?
（フェルン）シュタルク様は
I don't think you'll run.
逃げないと思います
（シュタルク）俺の何が分かる？
You think you know me?
（フェルン）
みじんも分かりませんが
I don't know the first thing about you, but
I recalled my own terrifying experience.
怖かったことを思い出したのです
（シュタルク）怖かったこと？
A terrifying experience?
My first battle against a monster.
（フェルン）
魔物と初めて戦った時です
I'd trained plenty until then.
修行は それまでに
十分すぎるほど積んできました
ですが 恐怖で足がすくみ
But my fear made me weak in the knees,
逃げだしてしまいました
and I ran.
The monster wouldn't stop chasing me.
どこまでも追ってくる魔物
For some reason, Ms. Frieren
wouldn't help me.
なぜか 助けてくれない
フリーレン様
（シュタルク）あ～
うちの師匠も そんな感じだわ
My master was like that, too.
（フェルン）
とうとう追い詰められ
When it finally cornered me
覚悟を決めた時
and I steeled my resolve,
my body moved.
体が動いたのです
必要なものは
覚悟だけだったのです
All I needed was resolve.
All the training you've done
won't let you down.
必死に積み上げてきたものは
決して裏切りません
シュタルク様は
どうしようもない臆病者ですが
Though you're a hopeless coward, I believe
your resolve to protect the village is real.
村を守りたいという覚悟だけは
きっと 本物だと思います
（シュタルク）覚悟か…
Resolve, huh?
（ドアの開閉音）
（フリーレン）どうだった？
How did it go?
（フェルン）分かりません
I don't know.
分かりませんが…
I don't know,
きっと 大丈夫だと思います
but I think it'll be all right.
He's not here.
（フェルン）いませんね
（フリーレン）逃げたか
I guess he ran.
期待していたんだけど
It's a shame. I had high hopes for him.
しかたがない
We have no choice.
フェルン　竜と追いかけっこだ
Fern, we're going to play tag
with the dragon.
（フェルン）え…
What?
Frieren.
（シュタルク）フリーレン
You need me to keep it busy
for thirty seconds, right?
足止めは30秒でいいんだよな？
You're late.
遅かったじゃん
ひとつ 約束してくれないか？
Will you promise me one thing?
俺が途中で死んだとしても
If I die during the battle,
I want you to finish off the dragon.
竜は必ず しとめてほしいんだ
Very well. I promise.
分かった　約束する
But why are you willing to go
that far for the villagers?
でも なぜ村の人たちのために
そこまでするの？
（シュタルク）フッ…
（フリーレン）何？
What?
（シュタルク）
いや 変な質問だと思ってな
I just thought it was a strange question.
俺は この村に３年もいたんだぜ
I've lived in this village for three years.
（フリーレン）短いね
That's not very long.
（シュタルク）超長(なげ)えよ
Like heck it isn't.
（シュタルク）
よし じゃあ 一丁やるか
Okay. Let's do this.
Your hands are trembling.
手が震えています
怖いものは怖いんだよ
I'm afraid, after all.
（フリーレン）フッ
（シュタルク）
笑うことはねえだろ
You don't have to laugh.
You're just like Eisen.
（フリーレン）アイゼンと同じだ
（シュタルク）師匠と？
My master?
（ヒンメル）
これは強敵だな
Now this is a powerful foe.
アイゼン　手が震えてる
怖いの？
Eisen, your hands are shaking.
Are you scared?
（アイゼン）ああ
Yeah.
You'd admit it, just like that?
（フリーレン）
あっさり認めるんだね
（アイゼン）怖がることは
悪いことではない
Being afraid isn't a bad thing.
この恐怖が
俺を ここまで連れてきたんだ
It's my fear that brought me this far.
You even tremble the same way.
震え方まで同じだ
（シュタルク）そうか
I see.
師匠も
My master was afraid, too.
怖かったんだな
必要なのは 覚悟だけだ
All I need is resolve.
（フリーレン）
竜の間合いに入った
He's entered the dragon's range.
It's not attacking.
攻撃してきませんね
It's being cautious.
（フリーレン）警戒している
I thought so.
やっぱり そうか
（息を吸い込む音）
（フリーレン）どうりで
村が襲われなくなったわけだ
No wonder it stopped attacking the village.
竜は賢い生き物だ
The dragon is a smart creature.
It's not stupid enough to pick a fight
against a powerful opponent.
強い相手に 自分から
ケンカを売りに行くような⸺
バカじゃない
アイゼンが
シュタルクを殴ったのは
Eisen didn't hit Stark for being weak,
あいつが弱かったからでも
or because he was disappointed in him.
失望したからでもない
（アイゼン）
ケンカ別れをしてしまっていてな
We parted in anger.
（フリーレン）殴ったの？
You hit him?
（アイゼン）
反射的に体が動いたんだ
My body moved on reflex.
かわいそうなことをしてしまった
I'm sorry for what I did to him.
怖かったんだ
I was afraid.
I was afraid of him, Frieren.
俺は怖かったんだよ フリーレン
I couldn't believe it.
こいつは すごいことだ
俺の弟子は…
My student will become
an incredible warrior.
とんでもない戦士になる
（シュタルクの力む声）
うあっ！
今だ！　撃ちまくれ
Now! Fire!
おい！　なんで撃たねえ
Hey, why aren't you shooting at it?
言われたとおりにやっただろ！
I did exactly what you told me to do!
１人で戦えってか！
You expect me to fight it myself?
ふざけんなよ クソババア！
You can't be serious, you old hag!
やっぱ お前も…
You're just like my master after all!
It's already dead.
もう死んでいるよ
What?
え…
クソババアか…
An old hag, huh?
（フェルン）あとが怖いな
I'm scared of what she'll do later.
（シュタルク）俺が…
I... killed it?
やったのか
俺が１人で
I defeated the dragon by myself?
竜を倒した
（フリーレン）シュタルク
Stark.
You did well.
よくやった
期待以上だ
You exceeded my expectations. Well done.
偉いぞ
宝の山だ　うひょ～！
Look at this mountain of treasure. Yippee!
（フェルン）
全部は持っていけませんよ
We can't take it all with us.
フッ…
No more than three items.
（フェルン）３つまでにしなさい
（シュタルク）
本当に くだらねえな
This is ridiculous.
You're interested in this stuff?
こんなものに夢中になれるのか
（フリーレン）宝の山だよ
This stuff is a mountain of treasure.
（シュタルク）師匠は
お前のせいで 勇者一行の冒険が
My master said that you made the
heroes' adventure ridiculous.
くだらないものになったって
言ってたぜ
（フリーレン）そう
Oh?
くだらなくて
He said it was a ridiculous and fun journey.
とても楽しい旅だったってよ
（ハイター）すごい！
本当に かき氷が出てきましたよ
Wow, you actually made shaved ice!
（フリーレン）フン
探索したかいがあったでしょ
I told you it was worth searching for.
（ハイター）しかも これ
シャリシャリじゃなくて
Not only that, but it's
fluffy instead of icy!
フワフワのやつですよ
（フリーレン）ホントだ
You're right.
（アイゼン）くだらん
This is ridiculous. Should we
be wasting time on this?
こんなことをしていて
いいのか？
（ヒンメル）別にいいじゃないか
Why not? Our journey's only just begun.
まだ 旅は始まったばかりなんだ
（アイゼン）
人類最強といわれた南の勇者も
The Hero of the South, said to be
humanity's strongest fighter,
魔王直下の七崩賢(しちほうけん)に討たれた
was defeated by the Demon King's
Seven Sages of Destruction.
We don't know if we'll make it back alive.
俺たちだって
生きて帰れるかどうか
分からないんだ
アイゼンは
つらく苦しい旅がしたいのかい？
Eisen, would you prefer a
difficult and painful journey?
I'd rather enjoy a ridiculous and fun
journey I can laugh about when it's over.
僕はね
終わったあとに
くだらなかったって
笑い飛ばせるような⸺
楽しい旅がしたいんだ
（ハイター）見てください ほら
Look! It melts as soon as you touch it!
触ると すぐに溶けてしまいます
（フリーレン）触っちゃダメだって
食べるんだから
Don't touch it. We're going to eat that.
（アイゼン）くだらん
Ridiculous.
（ハイター）ところで フリーレン
シロップは？
By the way, Frieren, what about syrup?
（フリーレン）
シロップを出す魔法はないよ
I don't have a spell to produce syrup.
（ヒンメル）ないんだ
You don't?
（アイゼン）本当にくだらんな
Truly ridiculous.
（フリーレン）
どう？　透けて見える？
Well? Can you see through them?
（フェルン）見えますが…
Yes, but it's not a very interesting spell.
あまり面白い魔法では
ありませんね
（フリーレン）悪かったね
面白い体じゃなくて
Sorry my body's not more interesting.
（シュタルク）ん？　何？
What?
ちっさ
So small.
（シュタルク）ちっさくねえよ！
I'm not small!
（フリーレン）それで
シュタルク これから どうする？
So, Stark, what will you do now?
別に アイゼンのところに
帰ってもいいんだよ
You can go back to Eisen, you know.
師匠が 俺を連れてけって
言ったんだろ
My master told you to take me
with you, didn't he?
それに…
Besides...
俺も くだらない旅が
したくなったんだ
I feel like going on a
ridiculous journey, too.
28 years after the death of Himmel the Hero, in the fortress city of Waal,
located in Riegel Canyon in the central lands
Monsters are active in the northern lands.
（衛兵隊長）
北側諸国は魔物の動きが活発でな
現在 関所の通行は
認められていない
No one's allowed to pass through
the checkpoint currently.
通れるようになるのは
いつ頃になりそうですか？
When will the checkpoint open again?
（衛兵隊長）さあな
Dunno.
少なくとも 俺が着任してからは
At the very least, we've let none
through since I was posted here,
魔物も 人も
１匹たりとも通していない
monsters and people alike.
（衛兵）失礼いたします
Excuse me.
Sir, the castellan would like to see you.
隊長　城代がお呼びです
（衛兵隊長）すぐ行く
I'll be right there.
Listen here, adventurers.
いいな 冒険者ども
この街で くれぐれも
問題は起こすなよ
Don't cause any trouble in this town.
That wasn't a very warm welcome.
（フェルン）
いい対応ではありませんでしたね
（フリーレン）そうだね
You're right. He's a good guard.
あれは優秀な衛兵だよ
Harsh on outsiders,
よそ者には厳しく
as town guards should be.
街を守る衛兵は かくあるべきだ
（シュタルク）ん？
（フリーレン）というわけで
Anyway, this city seems safe.
この街は安全そうだし
しばらく ここで待つとしよう
We'll wait here for a while.
久々に ゆっくり
魔法の研究ができるぞ
It'll be a good opportunity
to take our time studying magic.
宿に荷物を置いたら
魔法店に行こうっと
Once we drop our things off at the inn,
I'm going to the magic shops.
何だよ
What? The checkpoint's closed.
It's not like we have a choice.
関所が開いてないんだから
しょうがないじゃん
ほら ここで解散
Go on. You're free to go.
私 宿 取ってくるから
I'm going to get us a room at the inn.
Wanna get something to eat?
メシでも食いに行く？
うん　１人で行くね
Right. I'll go by myself.
Scary...
怖(こえ)え…
（村人）最近では 海路も
ダメになったって話だぜ
I heard the sea routes have
been shut down recently, too.
（村人）北側諸国の軍が
討伐に動くらしいが
The northern lands' army
plans to defeat them,
関所が開くのは
早くても２年は先だろうな
but it'll be at least two years
until the checkpoint opens.
商売あがったりだ
Business is at a standstill.
（シュタルク）懐かしいな
I haven't had this in forever.
ジャンボベリースペシャル
The jumbo-berry special.
I was just a kid when I came here before,
so I could hardly finish it.
前 来た時は ガキだったから
全部 食えなくて
師匠と分けたんだよな
I had to split it with my master.
I don't remember it being
this small, though.
でも こんな小さかったっけな
It seems that way because
you're all grown up now.
（マスター）そいつは 坊主が
大人になっちまったからだぜ
そうか
I see. I've gotten bigger, huh?
俺が大きくなったんだな
Everything seemed so big when I was a kid.
ガキの頃は
何もかもが大きかったのに
あれほど広かった
師匠の背中でさえ
Even my master's back that
once looked so broad
いつの間にか
小さくなっちまっていた
started looking small at some point.
（マスター）
アイゼンの旦那も もう年だ
Eisen's getting up there in age.
しっかり親孝行してやれよ
I hope you're being a dutiful student.
That's what I'm doing right now.
その最中だよ
でも ホントに
こんな小さかったっけな
Really, though, was it always this small?
（マスター）
時の流れってのは残酷だよなあ
The passage of time is cruel.
（シュタルク）ん？
何だよ　いいだろ 別に
What? Got a problem?
俺の金で買ったんだぜ
I bought it with my own money.
（フェルン）
すみません　ミルクください
Excuse me. Could I get a glass of milk?
（マスター）あいよ
Sure thing.
（シュタルク）えー 何？
なんで怒ってんの？
What? Why are you mad?
（フェルン）シュタルク様
Mr. Stark.
（シュタルク）
分かったよ　半分 あげるよ
Fine. You can have half.
（フェルン）そうではなくて
That's not what I was going to say.
この街で ２年以上
待つことになりそうだと言われたら
What if I told you we might have to
wait more than two years in this city?
どう思いますか？
え？　嫌だけど
What? No, thanks.
そうですよね　嫌ですよね！
Right? I don't want to, either.
（シュタルク）うん…
Uh, yeah.
何 この人
What's her deal?
（フェルン）安心しました
I'm relieved. You're normal.
シュタルク様って
普通だったんですね
（シュタルク）ねえ
俺 何か悪いことした？
Hey, did I do something to offend you?
（シュタルク）
関所を越える方法か…
A way through the checkpoint?
いいぜ　探すの手伝うよ
Sure, I'll help you look for one.
ありがとうございます
Thank you.
（シュタルク）飛んで
上から越えちまうってことは
Would it be possible to fly over it?
できないのか？
北側諸国との国境には
The border with the northern lands
限界高度まで
強力な結界が張られていて
is protected by a powerful barrier that
extends to maximum flying altitude.
通過できないそうです
It can't be crossed.
そりゃそうか
That makes sense. Otherwise flying
monsters would get right through.
じゃなきゃ 空の魔物が素通りだ
しかたがない
商人ギルドに当たるか
Then we have no choice.
We'll hit up the merchants' guild.
交易ぐらいは
しているかもしれない
They might at least be trading.
（フェルン）交易は全面封鎖
Trade has been shut down completely.
護衛をつけた隊商も禁止となると
If guarded caravans aren't allowed through,
北側は
よほど危険な状況のようですね
then the northern lands
must be quite dangerous.
We'll have to wait until
the situation settles down.
やはり 情勢が落ち着くまで
待つしか…
（シュタルク）いや
No, let's hit up the black market
and thieves' guild first.
闇市や盗賊ギルドの連中も
当たってみよう
Isn't that a bit dangerous?
さすがに それは
危なくないですか？
大丈夫
We'll be fine. People think I look pretty
strong, and I'm a decent bluffer.
俺って結構 強そうに見えるし
はったりも うまいんだぜ
And you've got the face of a scoundrel.
悪人顔ですしね
（シュタルク）うるせえ
Shut up.
（シュタルク）ダメか…
Well, that didn't work.
I shouldn't be surprised. They're
basically fighting a defensive battle.
そりゃそうだよな
防衛戦しているようなもんだ
There's nothing we can do
if the gates won't open.
門が開かなきゃ どうにもならねえ
よし
Well, we've got nothing to lose.
Let's visit the guard station next.
次は ダメもとで
衛兵の詰め所 行くか
何だよ
What?
I was just thinking you're being
especially cooperative.
（フェルン）いえ
シュタルク様が
とても協力的だと思いまして
（シュタルク）
お前が言いだしたことだろ
This was your idea.
待つのは嫌なんじゃないのか？
I thought you didn't want to wait.
私以上に必死なように見えます
You seem more desperate than me.
まあ…
Well, I don't have a lot of time.
あまり時間がないからな
どういうことですか？
What do you mean?
（シュタルク）
ここ いい景色だろ
The view from here is nice, isn't it?
北側が よく見える
You can see the north side clearly.
When I was little,
my master brought me here.
小さい頃
師匠に連れられて ここに来た
（アイゼン）
俺たちは この街から
We departed for the
northern lands from this city.
北側諸国に旅立ったんだ
（幼いシュタルク）
どんな旅だったんだ？　師匠
What was your journey like, Master?
（アイゼン）聞きたいか？
You wanna know? Back then, we...
あの時 俺たちは…
Normally he hardly spoke about himself,
（シュタルク）ふだんは
自分のことを何も話さないくせに
but he happily told me about
the heroes' adventure.
勇者一行の冒険を
楽しそうに語ったんだ
Across his long life,
師匠は 長い人生の中の
たった10年の冒険を
nothing was more important to him
than that ten-year adventure.
何よりも大切にしていた
きっと フリーレンだって
そうなんだろう
I'm sure the same is true for Frieren.
どうでしょうか
I wonder.
（シュタルク）師匠は もう
旅ができるような年じゃない
But he's too old to travel now.
そんな師匠が 俺を連れてけって
お前たちに言ったんだ
And he told you to take me with you.
だから 俺はよ
So I need to experience lots of
ridiculous and fun adventures in his place
師匠の代わりに
くだらなくて 楽しい旅を
たくさん経験して
土産話を たっぷりと
持って帰らないとダメなんだ
and bring back stories to tell him.
俺にできる恩返しは
このくらいだからさ
It's all I can do to repay my debt to him.
あんまり のんびりしていると
師匠が死んじまうんだ
If I take too long, my master will die.
（フェルン）フッ…
なら こんなところで
足止めはいけませんね
Then we can't allow ourselves
to be stopped here.
（シュタルク）まっ あの人は
まだまだ長生きしそうだけどな
I bet he's still got plenty
of years left, though.
（フェルン）フリーレン様
Ms. Frieren, what are you doing here?
こんなところで
何をやっているんですか？
（フリーレン）シッ　静かにして
Quiet.
追われてるんだよ
I'm being pursued.
な… 何やらかしたんだよ
Wh-What did you even do?
知らないよ
I don't know.
私は ただ魔法店を
ハシゴしていただけで…
I was just visiting various
magic shops, and then...
（シュタルク）あ…
I'm sorry, Ms. Frieren!
（衛兵隊長）
申し訳ありませんでした！
フリーレン様
どうか お許しください
Please forgive me!
待って…
Wait. I don't like where this is going.
すごく嫌な流れな気がする
It seems the guard captain was rude to you.
（城代）衛兵隊長が
無礼を働いたようですな
この街の城代として
謝罪いたします
As the castellan of this city,
I offer my apologies.
It doesn't bother me. He was
just doing his job as a guard.
いや 気にしてないよ
この人は
衛兵の仕事をしただけだし
私も まったく急いでなくて
むしろ のんびり…
I'm actually not in any kind of hurry.
I'm taking my time—
（城代）また 北側へ
旅立つおつもりなのですな
You plan to travel north again, don't you?
北側諸国は今
I hear the northern lands are currently
engaged in an endless conflict
魔王軍の残党との紛争が
絶えないと聞きます
with the remnants of the Demon King's forces.
You must be concerned about
the present situation.
現状を憂えてのことでしょう
その志 まさに英雄のごとし
Truly, you have the kindness of a hero.
The people of the northern lands
will be delighted as well.
北側諸国の民も喜ぶことでしょう
Please feel free to pass
through the checkpoint.
関所は ご自由にお通りください
（歓声と拍手）
こんなに簡単に通れるだなんて
I can't believe we're getting
through this easily.
Shouldn't we have told them
who you were from the start?
初めから フリーレン様の名前を
出していれば
よかったんじゃないですか？
言ってもムダだと
思っていたんだよ
I didn't think there was any point.
ゆっくりしたかったのに…
I wanted to take my time, anyway.
それに 私 こういうの
あまり好きじゃないんだよ
And I don't really like this kind of thing.
こんな光景 落ち着かないでしょ
It's an unsettling sight.
I'm glad I got to see it, though.
俺は 見れてよかったって
思っているぜ
師匠も こんな感じで
北側に旅立ったんだな
This must be how my master
departed for the north, too.
（フリーレン）そうだね
You're right.
あ～あ
魔法の研究したかったな
Aw, darn. I wanted to do
more magical research.
（フェルン）まだ言ってる
You're still saying that?
（シュタルク）大変だったんだぞ
あれから いろいろ
We went through a lot of trouble
after that, you know. Right?
（シュタルク）なあ
（フェルン）ええ
Yes.
♪～
And you alright
Can you hear me
Trailing along deserted train tracks
Crying excessively
Wanting you to smile
I hold on to memories I'd like to keep fresh
There's something I'd like to tell you
With words more precious than a goodbye
Unremarkable yet special
See, things that couldn't have been
Seen if it weren't for these eyes
Why? They begin to overflow
So, if I were to be born again
I would surely choose this place once more
So, if we were to meet again
I'd never let you go, I'd choose the present
Even if no promises were made
Even if I'm lost in days of loneliness
Those tears will be alright,
dawn will surely break
I'm whispering our lullaby
～♪
for you to come back home
It hurts...
Humans love to make a fuss.
He died in battle against
Aura ten years ago.
Mom...
The Liberation Festival is tonight.
Then we'd be no different from the demons.
They're capable of speech.
I'm curious about that mage.
What a pain in the rear...
Episode 7
Like a Fairy Tale
It's like a fairy tale.